<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Welcome to my Website</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive control</title>
      <link>/project/cog-control-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/cog-control-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cognitive control enables individuals to rapidly adapt to changing task demands. To investigate error-driven adjustments in cognitive control, in one study we have considered performance changes in posterror trials, when participants performed a visual search task requiring detection of angry, happy, or neutral facial expressions in crowds of faces. Whereas current models always predict a slowing down of performance after an error, we found the opposite result: when participants failed to detect the presence of a threatening face, in the following trial they were more efficient: their RTs tended to be faster with no accuracy cost.  The impact of threat-detection failure on cognitive control, as revealed by the present study, suggests that posterror adjustments should be understood as the product of domain-specific mechanisms that are strongly influenced by affective information, rather than as the effect of a general-purpose error-monitoring system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Working Memory</title>
      <link>/project/wm-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 19:51:32 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/wm-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Visual working memory (VWM) is a core executive function and plays a fundamental role  in our everyday lives. It is well known that the capacity of VWM is severely limited, but we poorly understand which information is stored and how is selected. A line of research studies the fidelity of memory representations in order to better understand the contents of VWM. In one study, we assessed the fidelity of VWM for faces and non-face objects. In two experiments, four levels of memory load (1, 2, 3, or 4 items) were combined with four perceptual distances between probe and study items, with maximum item confusability occurring for the minimum memory load. Under these conditions, recognition memory for multiple faces exceeded that of a single face. This result was primarily due to the higher false alarm rates for faces than non-face objects, even though the two classes of stimuli had been matched for perceptual discriminability. Control experiments revealed that this counter-intuitive result emerged only for old–new recognition choices based on near-threshold image differences. For non-face objects, instead, recognition performance decreased with increasing memory load. It is speculated that the low memorial discriminability of the transient properties of a face may serve the purpose of enhancing recognition at the individual-exemplar level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caudek, C. (2013). The fidelity of visual memory for faces and non-face objects. &lt;em&gt;Acta psychologica&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;143(1)&lt;/em&gt;, 40-51.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face Processing</title>
      <link>/project/face-aftereffect-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 19:44:32 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/face-aftereffect-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are all face experts. A highly debated topic is whether faces are processed differently from other objects. In one of the studies that we have carried out to explore the nature of face processing, we have examined the prioritization of attention to emotional faces. It has been hypothesized that a rapid response to a threatening face in a crowd is important to successfully interact in social environments. In our study, a visual search tasks was employed to determine whether there is a processing advantage for detecting an angry face in a crowd, compared to a happy face. In the literature, the empirical findings supporting the &lt;em&gt;anger superiority effect&lt;/em&gt; (ASE) have been criticized on the basis of possible low-level visual confounds and because of the limited ecological validity of the stimuli. Moreover, a &lt;em&gt;happiness superiority effect&lt;/em&gt; is usually found with more realistic stimuli. In our study, we tested the ASE by using dynamic (and static) images of realistic human faces, with validated emotional expressions having similar intensities, after controlling the bottom-up visual saliency and the amount of image motion. In five experiments, we found strong evidence for an ASE when using dynamic displays of facial expressions, but not when the emotions were expressed by static face images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ceccarini, F., &amp;amp; Caudek, C. (2013). Anger superiority effect: The importance of dynamic emotional facial expressions. &lt;em&gt;Visual Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21(4)&lt;/em&gt;, 498-540.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual differences in STWM biases.</title>
      <link>/project/depression-stwm-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/depression-stwm-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cognitive model of depression hypothesize that depressed and cognitive vulnerable individuals are prone to emotional biases in attention, interpretation, and memory  which could exacerbate distress. In one project, we studied the effects of negative cognitive style, sad mood, and facial affect on the short-term memory for the self-face and for other faces.
Following a sad mood induction, we examined the effect on working memory of an incidental association between facial affect, facial identity, and head-pose orientation. We found that participants high in negative cognitive style who experienced higher levels of sadness displayed a stronger self-face advantage (SFA) for sad expressions than happy expressions. The remaining participants displayed an opposite bias (a stronger SFA for happy expressions than sad expressions), or no bias. These findings highlight the importance of trait-vulnerability status in the working memory biases related to emotional facial expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caudek, C., &amp;amp; Monni, A. (2013). Do you remember your sad face? The roles of negative cognitive style and sad mood. &lt;em&gt;Memory&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21(8)&lt;/em&gt;, 891-903.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
