<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Corrado Caudek | Welcoming Uncertainty</title>
    <link>/author/corrado-caudek/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/corrado-caudek/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Corrado Caudek</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/author/corrado-caudek/featured.jpg</url>
      <title>Corrado Caudek</title>
      <link>/author/corrado-caudek/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive inflexibility specificity for individuals with high levels of obsessive-compulsive symptoms</title>
      <link>/publication/journal-article/2020_jbct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/journal-article/2020_jbct/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anger superiority effect: The importance of dynamic emotional facial expressions</title>
      <link>/publication/journal-article/2013_vc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/journal-article/2013_vc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
n our study, a visual search tasks was employed to determine whether there is a processing advantage for detecting an angry face in a crowd, compared to a happy face. In the literature, the empirical findings supporting the &lt;em&gt;anger superiority effect&lt;/em&gt; (ASE) have been criticized on the basis of possible low-level visual confounds and because of the limited ecological validity of the stimuli. Moreover, a &lt;em&gt;happiness superiority effect&lt;/em&gt; is usually found with more realistic stimuli. In our study, we tested the ASE by using dynamic (and static) images of realistic human faces, with validated emotional expressions having similar intensities, after controlling the bottom-up visual saliency and the amount of image motion. In five experiments, we found strong evidence for an ASE when using dynamic displays of facial expressions, but not when the emotions were expressed by static face images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ceccarini, F., &amp;amp; Caudek, C. (2013). Anger superiority effect: The importance of dynamic emotional facial expressions. &lt;em&gt;Visual Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21(4)&lt;/em&gt;, 498-540.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
